<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
	<link type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" id="dark-mode-custom-link"/>
	<link type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" id="dark-mode-general-link"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-custom-style"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-native-style"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-native-sheet"/>
	<channel>
		<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
		<atom:link href="http://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
		<link>http://flare145.com</link>
		<description>Official rss feed for FLARE145'S blog! Updates on new projects or random boring things.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<image>
			<url>http://flare145.com/res/blogicon128.png</url>
			<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/</link>
			<width>128</width>
			<height>128</height>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>Throw away thoughts on Boxkid</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=throw-away-thoughts-on-boxkid</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=throw-away-thoughts-on-boxkid</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">9/6/23</p>
<p>I've drawn 10 pages of my upcoming comic Boxkid Vs. the Ocean, although I'm not done editing them. I've been estimating Ch.1 to be about 30 pages in length, but I'm suddenly forced to make some release decisions right now.</p>
<p>I would feel comfortable releasing these 10 pages, but in terms of the story, nothing really happens in those first pages. I'd want the first chapter to feel like the first part of a pilot episode, but right now, it feels like the opening minute. Again, I'd be fine with this, but it would be months before anyone would be able to see a continuation, and therefore months before people really find out what the story is actually about.</p>
<p>Shorter chapters would let me update the comic more often, but the reader might not feel as satisfied. Especially at the beginning. So I'm not entirely sure what to do.</p>
<p>I said that BK was going to be my project that I care the least about, so I'm leaning towards the quicker releases. It will make less sense, but I think it's better to have something out there. Once things start to make more sense, more people will get interested. Hopefully the art style attracts readers on it's own.</p>
<p>The one thing is that I wonder if I should call the updates something other than chapters. I think chapter might imply something a lot longer, and in my head, I would know how many chapters constitute a "complete chapter." Maybe I'm not making any sense.</p>
<p>Okay so uh. Did I say anything of importance? Not sure. I guess if there's anything to take away from this, it's that BK might start soon. Or it might not. Thanks for reading! See you then hopefully</p>
 ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Insanely Productive Day</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=insanely-productive-day</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=insanely-productive-day</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">8/31/23</p>
<p>So lately, a lot of my free time has been going into gaming. Other than gaming though, I've been working on the CoaXion website. Still a lot to do but progress is chugging along. Something interesting happened today though.</p>
<p>I was trying to set up for potentially working on more DMCR achievement icons soon. I realized some of my files were still stuck on my old computer hard drive, so I had to go find and retrieve the files from there. While I was in there though, I figured I'd grab a few more files I hadn't had the time to transfer before. I ended up transferring the files for some old animation projects. Specifically Tankforce and Club Penguin Dance. Because I now had access to these again, I figured I'd make proper project pages for them. So that's what I did.</p>
<p>I didn't proof-read them at all, and I'm probably forgetting a lot of cool behind the scenes information, but the pages should be live now. I'll update them later on if I have to. I also finished another tiny animation for Dial-Up Studios today. I'll probably post about that again soon.</p>
<p>Yesterday there was a blue super moon, and I managed to take decent pictures of it. I put them together into like, one hdr picture. If I have time tomorrow, I might make it into a fun friday video. So yeah, really trippy how much I've done today. And seemingly out of nowhere too. </p>
<p>And finally to update on Boxkid: it's still goin. Slower this week because I worked on some extra stuff as mentioned above. I'm realizing that I might have to launch it next year if I don't speed up my process. Good thing I have no deadline or anything.</p>
<p>That's all for today. Gonna go game now probably bye</p>
 ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Boxkid clay model</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=boxkid-clay-model</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=boxkid-clay-model</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">8/3/23</p>
<p>I made a Boxkid clay model! I don't really know why. Well I know why. I was feeling bummed out and needed something to distract myself. I think I made this last week? Don't remember. Doesn't really matter. Is cool</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/080323boxkid.jpg" alt="clay model of my character boxkid" style="width:45vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>The kid is real</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/080323boxkid2.jpg" alt="clay model of my character boxkid" style="width:45vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>The kid is real again</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/080323boxkid3.jpg" alt="clay model of my character boxkid" style="width:45vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>One last pic for good measure</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I used some like, oil based clay? The one that doesn't dry. So I destroyed it because it wasn't actually cool enough to justify keeping it around. I'll prob make a digital model at some point to help me draw some panels down the line.</p>
<p>Speaking of, my progress on drawing the first chapter has slowed significantly. At least it doesn't matter too much since Boxkid isn't important. One of the reasons I've slowed down is that I've been putting more effort into making a website for CoaXioN. It's going smooth enough, but my brain feels filled to the brim with janky javascript code now. Portions of my brain are split between the different complex systems I've made for each of my websites. Blog posts are handled one way here, chapters of BK are handled a different way, and the blog posts for CoaXioN will also require a new system. It's hard not to get all of the different methods for stuff mixed up. Oh well. It's probably good for me to stress my brain a bit.</p>
<p>But yeah, I'm up to drawing page 6 of Boxkid. Am pretty happy with it but I know most people will not get it or will not care. But that's fine. Boxkid doesn't really get it or care either. In fact, I care so little that I'm not even going to finish thi</p>
 ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Boxkid progress</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=boxkid-progress</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=boxkid-progress.html</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">7/26/23</p>
<p>I haven't been working on Boxkid at full force, and I don't think I ever will. There's gonna be long wait times in between chapters. This is just so I don't waste all of my time doing one thing. I've also been working on other stuff like finishing the Coaxion logo (it looks awesome) and making a Coaxion website too. Well I haven't technically started on the website but I will. Oh I also streamed again too, so that was fun. I beat Half-Life 2 episode 1 in a single livestream. This means I just have to play episode 2 and then I'll be mostly caught up with Half-Life. Oh wow oh no this is a long and unstructured paragraph. Lets just end it bruh</p>
<p>Okay fresh paragraph for me to ruin. Let's get back to Boxkid. I spent a lot of time recently just establishing standards and formats for myself. Really small stuff like panel line width and trying to figure out how I want to letter the comic. I wanted to figure this stuff out first so that there can be some consistency in the comic. So yeah, kind of got the hang of that and now I think I have established a production pipeline for this project. I'm currently done drawing 4 pages of the comic, and 3 of those are completely ready. I'm hoping that I can end this first chapter in 30 pages, so according to that, I'm a tenth of the way done.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/072623boxkid.jpg" alt="some pages thrown about a bed with drawings of boxkid" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>Working on Boxkid</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I'll update this soon with more Boxkid news. I want to see if I can produce at a faster rate now that I have my process down. See you next update!</p> ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Back at studio A</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=back-at-studio-a</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=back-at-studio-a</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">7/18/23</p>
<p>In my head, I like to think of my room as studio A. Just for fun. And wherever I physically am is studio B. Anyways ignore this thought, let's just get to the news.</p>
<p>So yeah, I'm back from Chicago. Was awesome and I can't wait to go again. Now that I'm back home, I have more tools available to me to finish that Coaxion logo. I think I'll probably stream that later today. If not soon.</p>
<p>Now onto some more interesting stuff. The blog now has an official rss feed! If you don't know what that is, I wouldn't be surprised. It's actually pretty annoying to explain to people so I won't try to right now. You can look it up if you are curious. If you know what rss means than this is cool, but if you don't, it's not something you should worry about. The link for the rss feed isn't public on the website yet, so I'll drop a link here so you can access it early if you'd like. You can follow <a href="http://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="noopener" target="_blank">my rss feed</a> on your preferred feed reader.</p>
<p>Along with this update, individual blog posts now have unique urls. You might remember that I <a href="http://flare145.com/blogpost?=what-no-creative-outlet-does-to-a-mf" rel="noopener" target="_blank">tried to do this before</a>, but my new method is better. I mainly did this so that the rss feed can link to it's corresponding blog post. Oh and if you're wondering why I'm suddenly going all in on this rss stuff, it's so that I can make an rss feed for Boxkid. So every time a new chapter releases, you would see the update if you follow the rss feed. I'm thinking of more ways to make sure people can easily hear of a new chapter release. Prob just do a twitter account or something. Maybe email list? I think that might cost me some money so no.</p>
<p>Uhhhhh yeah no more updates for today I think. I'll start drawing actual pages of boxkid soon so stay tuned for that.</p> ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>FLARE145 goes to Chicago</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=flare145-goes-to-chicago</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=flare145-goes-to-chicago</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">7/4/23</p>
<p>I been in Chicago for the past week and I'm staying for like two more. I'm here because I'm visiting family and I've been having a great time.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/070423chicago.png" alt="A view of the city of chicago" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>The windy city</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I have plenty of free time considering I'm on vacation and all, so of course I started to work on random projects. First, I've been working on a tattoo design for some friends. I don't really have a deadline for that so it tends to be something I work on only when I feel like it. Next, I've been messing with making a logo for <a href="https://www.moddb.com/company/conc-studios" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Coaxion</a>, which is currently still known as Concussion Studios. They are currently rebranding, so from this point forward I will only refer to them as Coaxion. Multiple people are working on the logo, so my designs might not ever make it. So here's a look at one of them for funsies.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/070423coaxion.png" alt="Coaxion" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>A wip version of the logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Speaking of Coaxion, they just showed <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/deathmatch-classic-refragged" rel="noopener" target="_blank">DMCR</a> at <a href="https://www.dokomi.de/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Dokomi</a>, which is a big anime expo in Germany. They had these cool demo machines for the game which where decorated with some the achievement icons I designed a while back. It's trippy to see something I worked on out in the world. I'm happy for the Coaxion people and <a href="https://pjx.carrd.co/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PJX</a>, who is the dev who represented at Dokomi.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/070423dokomi.png" alt="Demo machines for DMCR" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>Taken by PJX at Dokomi 2023</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Okay last thing. If you follow me on twitter you know that I'm really into the idea of Boxkid. I talked about this last blogpost, but it's basically just a webcomic idea. While I don't feel comfortable actually starting the comic from where I am, I can still work on all of the surrounding aspects. Which is a lot actually. Mainly the website. I haven't bought a domain for it yet but it's currently live on <a href="http://boxkid.flare145.com" rel="noopener" target="_blank">boxkid.flare145.com</a>. It's very much a work in progress, although the plan for the finished website probably won't look very impressive. I just need to be able to serve pages for people to read. But yeah check it out if you want to see my concept images.</p>
<p>And that's about it. Stay tuned for more info on Boxkid as that is the main thing I'm currently passionate about. Until next time</p> ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>