<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
	<link type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" id="dark-mode-custom-link"/>
	<link type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" id="dark-mode-general-link"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-custom-style"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-native-style"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-native-sheet"/>
	<channel>
		<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
		<atom:link href="http://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
		<link>http://flare145.com</link>
		<description>Official rss feed for FLARE145'S blog! Updates on creative projects and thoughts on various other topics.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<image>
			<url>http://flare145.com/res/blogicon128.png</url>
			<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/</link>
			<width>128</width>
			<height>128</height>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[test 4/7]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=test-47</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=test-47</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 01:54:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>Hey! This is a test related to rss stuff, so if you're seeing this, you are cool. Basically, I'm just making sure the date is formatted correctly. Let's see what happens.</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[RSS feed is back?]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=rss-feed-is-back</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=rss-feed-is-back</guid>
			<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>For a while now, I’ve been wanting to bring back my RSS feed. You might remember that you used to be able to subscribe to my blog this way. I updated it from the post <a href="https://flare145.com/blogpost?=flare145-goes-to-chicago" rel="nopener" target="_blank">FLARE145 goes to Chicago</a> to <a href="http://flare145.com/blogpost?=cool-little-animation-for-coaxion" rel="nopener" target="_blank">Cool little animation for Coaxion</a>, but it was too big of a hassle for something that was unnecessary. Well, in trying to once again improve how I post the blog, I managed to make it much easier for me to maintain an RSS feed. So, if you use a feed reader, be sure to subscribe to my <a href="http://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="nopener" target="_blank">RSS feed</a>!</p>
				<p>I will probably actually support it for a long time now. With the improvements to my system, it’s less work to make a post, even with the added step of the RSS feed. I’ll put a proper link to it somewhere on this page too, because I don’t think I ever had one.</p>
				<p>Another reason I wanted to do this is because of my dream of making my own feed reader. I likely won’t get around to doing this ever, but I want to make a feed reader that looks like a little plaza of characters, each one representing a feed. They would be customization so you can make them look like your friends sona or something, and have them walk around with that friend’s feed. I just think it would be cool, but it’s probably impossible for me to ever make.</p>
				<p>I’ve got some stuff to do so I’ll sign off for now. Did you notice I’ve been making more posts? I’ve been in a writing mood lately. Not sure how long this will last for, but I do at least have one more post I’ve been typing out for a bit. Not sure what day I’ll post it, but probably soon. Until then, see ya</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2]]>
			</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=nintendo-switch-2</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=nintendo-switch-2</guid>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2025</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>Nintendo recently presented their new console, and I’m really excited for it.</p>
				<p>I understand that those prices are looking very high, and in particular, I see no reason for any of the accessories to be priced that high. But thankfully, I’m in a situation where a lot of the money I make is just getting saved, and I really don’t mind spending on a console and game. It would only amount to like ¾ a paycheck which I can totally do right now. The sadder thing is that if I get the new job I’m trying to get, I probably wouldn’t even have time to play it.</p>
				<p>The new Mario Kart looks so good. I was expecting a new game to be vastly different since Mario Kart 8 is the peak of the current formula, and they definitely delivered. Mario Kart is one of those games I love to play forever, and I recently got into Forza Horizon 5 in a similar way. The new game feels like a combination of both in some ways, so it’s literally peak. </p>
				<p>Donkey Kong Bonanza is also another reminder of why I’m always drawn to Nintendo games. It really is like “indie games with a budget.” What I mean is that they make really polished games that often incorporate new and unique gameplay ideas. There is not a game that you can currently play that is like Donkey Kong Bonanza. You can play other 3d platformers, but none feature the same mechanics. I’ve been thinking about destructible environments in games recently, mostly because of how they were implemented in Marvel Rivals. I think it’s one of the cooler aspects of Marvel Rivals, and I was thinking about how this feels like something that wasn’t really possible to make until now. With Nintendo, they try to look for this kind of thing. What is possible now with new hardware that wasn’t possible before. With the Switch 2 hardware, they’ve been able to make a destructible environment system that blows Marvel Rivals out of the water. Obviously, there are more constraints with Rivals because it’s designed in a way that facilitates a playable competitive map (very impressive), but I’m still really impressed with what I’ve seen in Donkey Kong. </p>
				<p>Everything is possible first on pc, and really, indie games prove that pretty much anything is possible on low spec hardware as well. But it’s the combination of quality visuals and design with unique ideas that makes me so excited about Nintendo games. I don’t like to call myself a Nintendo fan, but I am. If they stopped making good games, then I’d stop being a fan. But if you erased my memory and put games from across the industry in front of me, I’d be most drawn to Minecraft. But then after that it would probably be a Nintendo game. So yeah.</p>
				<p>Things have been getting better for 3d platformer fans though. A lot of pc games like Super Lucky’s Tale, or upcoming ones like Rolling Rascal. Even Sony’s Astrobot almost made me want to get a Playstation, but that’s the only game I’d really be interested in, so maybe in like 10 years. </p>
				<p>The closer we get to the end of support for Windows 10, the more I feel like I want to switch to Linux as my pc operating system. I now have a vision of a future where my pc is linux, and I do most of my gaming on a separate dedicated device. Currently, something like a Steam Deck would be best for this, but seeing the performance of the Switch 2, I can see a near future where I do this with the Switch. Just an interesting idea.</p>
				<p>That’s all for now. Just wanted to ramble because I’m really excited. The cool thing about being older is that you can actually wait for things you “can’t wait for.” In the mean time, I’ve got peak to play (Crab Champions).</p>]]>
			</description>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>