<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
		<atom:link href="https://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
		<link>https://flare145.com</link>
		<description>Official rss feed for FLARE145'S blog! Updates on creative projects and thoughts on various other topics.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<image>
			<url>https://flare145.com/res/blogicon128.png</url>
			<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com</link>
			<width>128</width>
			<height>128</height>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[Money just actually makes you happy]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=money-just-actually-makes-you-happy</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=money-just-actually-makes-you-happy</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 19:41:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>For a long time now I’ve tried to refrain from talking too much about how I’m doing internally, mostly because it would have made reading this blog really unpleasant. I prefer talking about my creative projects, but lately, I haven’t had much time to focus on that stuff. So, Even though I already gave a personal update with my posts about my new job, I thought I’d make yet another personal update where I talk about my new job.</p>
				<p>Basically, I’m actually just a happy person now. It’s not like I’m making a ton of money, but I feel financially secure enough to not worry too much about upping my income immediately, so my free time is actually spent not worrying about the future. I kind of thought financial security wouldn’t bring me this happiness because most of my unhappiness comes from depression, but I’ve been getting better at handling that over the past few years. I’m finally at a healthy point mentally, and that happened to line up with the added financial security. The new job is also just generally rewarding in a way that makes me feel like I’ve achieved some form of self-actualization. I kind of attributed my depression to random stupid brain chemical stuff because my more serious episodes occurred seemingly at random, but I realize now that some of it was probably informed by my low self worth. My self worth is finally in the green so to say, and it’s definitely making a difference.</p>
				<p>I guess a big part of this for me is that I derive fulfillment from making things. I find my job fulfilling because I get to make cool signs. Actually I found my old retail job fulfilling too, it just wasn’t going to make me a living. </p>
				<p>In animated movies, for some reason there’s this trend of the protagonist finding fulfillment in one movie, and then suddenly they neeed a romantic partner in the second movie to feel happy at all. Well, I’m happy to confirm this doesn’t happen in real life. At least not with me. I actually don’t think I’m suited for romantic relationships at all, because my happiness and fulfillment come from things that are counter to relationships. I’m an artist, and I love making art, but people forget that making art is very very lonely. I don’t mind it. In fact, I often think about a world where I don’t have any social relationships at all. I think I would do fine, but in the end, I still like having a few friends. Its fun, and fun isn’t something I want to entirely strip out of my life. Anyways, I was mostly bringing this relationship stuff because I guess I expected that to be the next thing I want out of life, but it’s really not. I think about it a bit, but I think mostly it would just get in the way of the rest of what I do. </p>
				<p>So yeah, moral of the story is that happiness is possible. Even if you are antisocial, unemotional, or otherwise a idiot. Find your fulfilling actions, learn the ebb and flow of your low points, and find security in your future. That wasn’t very many words but it represents a lot of hard work, so it really isn’t easy or simple. But it is achievable. I hope this maybe makes feel someone feel inspired or something idk. A lot of this comes down to stuff outside your own control, but I guess the best you can do is try and be prepared for when things could be in your control.</p>
				<p>That’s all for now. See ya later</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[GUYS GET ON THE THLOG]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=guys-get-on-the-thlog</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=guys-get-on-the-thlog</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 03:26:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>Okay first, lemme explain why I'm late like a week to making the post I said I would. After coming back from camping, I've been really busy. Mostly it's just me being tired from work, but also I had some errands pile up so I basically haven't done anything interesting on my own time for the past week. My mini social media break did go well though, and I'm likely to try something similar again, maybe this time without youtube as well.</p>
				<p>Okay but now for what really matters. The thlog is real. My friend Tholp just updated their <a href="https://tholps.site/" rel="nopener" target="_blank">website</a> so go check it out! It's got aura and a blog.</p>
				<p>Oh also I just remembered another reason I didn't post was that I kinda messed up my method for making posts on my phone. I haven't been on the pc much lately but when I tried to post from my phone, I didn't bother fixing it. So yeah, hopefully I fix that soon because it's more convenient for when I'm tired.</p>
				<p>Speaking of, I'm way too tired rn. see ya later</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[Quick update on my absence]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=quick-update-on-my-absence</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=quick-update-on-my-absence</guid>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 13:50:15 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>I've been taking a break from my biggest distractions (bluesky and discord) and it's been going very well. I got some decent work done on my commission work and I finished watching the new squid games (it was good?). I initially intended to write more updates here, but when I was on the computer, I really was only working.</p>
				<p>Anyways, there actually is a reason I'm forcing myself to write this update though. I totally forgot that I'm going camping this weekend for 4th of July. I'm driving there today after work, so when Saturday comes, I might still be absent. It depends on whether or not I get signal there. </p>
				<p>That's all I have the time to write at the moment. If I get signal where I'm camping, I might write a more detailed blog post about how my break went. See you then hopefully</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[A little experiment]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=a-little-experiment</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=a-little-experiment</guid>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 05:33:07 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>This week, I've suddenly found the motivation to try to make quick progress on things I'd like to get done. Right now, my personal project priorities are Boxkid chapter 2, and then RSS Plaza. Before that, I still need to finish another logo commission, so that has even higher priority. I've devised a small experiment that might help me in being more productive this week.</p>
				<p>I'm not letting myself use Discord or Bluesky this week. At least until Saturday. I predict that this will lead me to spend more time working and gaming, and the hope is that I have the will to force myself to work more than game. I'm not completely stopping myself from opening Discord because I need it to talk to my commission client, but I will be refraining from using it any more than I have to.</p>
				<p>I might be making more posts here because of boredom. We'll see. I'll make sure to make a post at the end at least to go over the results of this. Wish me luck!</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[I have the coolest job ever]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=i-have-the-coolest-job-ever</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=i-have-the-coolest-job-ever</guid>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 16:53:29 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>I have now worked my first full week of my new job. It's been really great so far. I'm learning a lot and I feel like I am learning quickly. 8 hours there goes by really quick, so even though I'm working way more than I used to, I don't feel overwhelmed. An 8 hour shift at my old job felt so much worse. I think it's mostly because I find this job so much more interesting, but it could also be because I'm not dealing with the most annoying customers in the world. </p>
				<p>Now that I've worked for a bit, I have a better sense of how this will effect my creative output. Basically, I should still be able to work on stuff. This week, I've just been gaming when I get home though. If I see my friends online, it's nice to just talk and game for a bit since I talk with them less now. There's no urgency to my personal projects, so I've been feeling really relaxed. Will likely work on RSS Plaza next week. Just a little bit.</p>
				<p>In other news, I just managed to order a Switch 2 from Walmart yesterday, so I'm really excited to play that when it gets here next week. The nice thing about having a full time job that I intend to stay at for a long time is that I can actually game without any guilt again. Life is pretty awesome now.</p>
				<p>Also weekends are so back?! The weekend became meaningless to me because my old job would schedule me different every week, so I was never guaranteed any consistent off days. Now I always have Saturday and Sunday off which is cool. Maybe my sense of the passage of time will improve. It certainly feels nicer at least.</p>
				<p>That's all I got for now. Hope you're having a great day and see ya later</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[My last day at work]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=my-last-day-at-work</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=my-last-day-at-work</guid>
			<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 04:36:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>Today was my final day at my retail job. I worked there for almost three years. Right now, I’m filled with such a unique feeling of relief and sadness. I was so sick of working there, but I’m also so sad to say goodbye to my coworkers. I’ve worked with some of them for a long time, but even people I haven’t known that long have been pleasant to work with. I’m going to miss working there. I’m going to miss the feeling of working there.</p>
				<p>I’ve been trying to get a new job for a while now, and something I find interesting is that although I am sad to leave, the point at which I would have been saddest to leave has already passed. I think that within the last year, I began to feel more disconnected with that environment. In the three years I worked there, I worked under five different managers. It almost feels like I worked five different jobs. So instead of this feeling like the end of the massive era of working this job, it feels more like the end of the latest era at that job. My favorite times are long gone, but things are looking up right now too. 
</p>
				<p>There are so many vibes I’m gonna miss. There was something cool about having a part-time retail job and thinking about logo commissions I needed to work on after work. It made me feel kind of Peter Parker. I feel like every lunch was a vibe too. Like I always felt that I was meant for more, but I was stuck where I was. Yet, I still enjoyed those moments. I even enjoyed working so hard I felt delirious. The days I will miss the most are the truck days. I’d go to work at 4 in the morning and unload new merchandise. If I had the motivation to move quickly, those days left me really exhausted, but I liked it. I liked the feeling of being there early, working hard, and getting home early. It’s hard to explain. </p>
				<p>I have a hard time with managing time for friends, so generally, I only really talk to a few people. That’s why it was really nice that I got along with mostly everyone I worked with. It felt like I had more friends. I’m a little worried now that my new job won’t feel like that, because it will be like I have less friends. I’m okay with that though. It’s just sad to lose contact with these people I came to care about. One of my coworkers even drew me a little Boxkid as goodbye! It’s so cool. I would have included a picture of it here, but it’s a bit late and I’m too tired to set up the picture to post here. I plan to include it in a fanart section on the Boxkid website. I have a couple of pieces of fanart now, so I’ll probably do that soon.
</p>
				<p>Without a doubt, I would not be who I am now without this job. The part-time schedule enabled me to grow my art skills in my own time. And all of those projects that I spent my time and energy on are what allowed me to land my new job. So much happened in the time I worked here. Fun Friday, Coaxion stuff, logo commissions, Axo x Minecraft, and Boxkid. I even like looking back at the movies and shows I watched. The job was the ever present backdrop to anything I did, so it does feel weird that it’s gone now.</p>
				<p>I’m so excited for my next job. I finally feel like I ended up where I’m supposed to be. Hopefully, that’s the feeling I have when I’m working there. I guess I don’t really know yet. This is also going to be the most I’ve ever worked consistently in terms of hours, so we’ll see how I handle that. Overall though, I’m very very happy. 
</p>
				<p>You know what’s crazy though. This blog started before having this job. For some reason that seems crazy to me, but it’s obviously true. You can read me being a little student experimenting with HTML & CSS. It’s a little comforting to know that part of my life is still the same. I’m still FLARE145. I was making stuff before, and I’ll be making stuff after.</p>
				<p>Speaking of, what’s next for creative stuff? I’m not sure. It depends on how I handle working this new job. If I get home exhausted everyday, I’m unlikely to have the motivation to do much. I’m trying to stay hopeful that this won’t be the case though. So, probably, I’ll have to put a hold on RSS Plaza. I get the feeling that would require more time and energy at the moment. If I work on anything, it’s more likely to be Boxkid. There’s still a lot of work to do for the next chapter, but I feel that it is more manageable in smaller chunks than RSS Plaza is. But honestly, idk. Axo x Minecraft stays on sleep for now too. And of course, the infamous Rainbow animation is also not a priority. At some point in the future, I’m going to release another set of artwork. At work, I had managers that were okay with me drawing when it got slow, so I ended up with a total of about 100 pages of fun little doodles. I want to post them on my website, but I need to scan them, and then censor any sensitive information like stuff about my jobs location or coworkers names. I don’t know how much of that there is, so I’ll have to check. It’s gonna be awesome when it comes out though. I’m thinking it could be a daily release thing. Some kind of regular release like that would be cool I think.</p>
				<p>Thanks for reading. I’ll be nervously waiting to start my new job, and enjoying a feeling of freedom from my old one. I’ll see you later.</p>
]]>
			</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[I switched to Linux already]]>
			</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=i-switched-to-linux-already</link>
			<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=i-switched-to-linux-already</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 18:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[<p>Okay so last week when I said I was considering switching to Linux, I kind of thought I would do it later in the year. Turns out I had the motivation and interest to do it now, so I installed openSUSE Tumbleweed on my desktop computer about 5 days ago. It’s a dual-boot setup so I can easily launch Windows 10 on a separate drive. I thought I'd talk a bit about my experience so far, but be warned. This is probably going to be a boring post. Also I don't actually know what I'm doing so I'm probably going to say stuff that is incorrect in this. Just ignore. Thank you.</p>
				<h3>Installing graphics card drivers</h3>
				<p>The first hurdle I encountered was installing Nvidia’s proprietary driver for my graphics card. I tried various methods suggested online, but it took until maybe the fourth hour of my efforts to find one random Reddit comment that solved my issue. No idea how I would’ve fixed it without that comment.</p>
				<p>Despite it being such a hassle, the feeling I got when it finally worked was incredible. I can’t really describe it. Usually when you do something like this, you’re glad that you finally don’t have to deal with it anymore. In this case, it was that same feeling but additionally, I felt like I had learned something.</p>
				<p>Installing video and audio codecs after this was super easy, and I ran into little trouble.</p>
				<h3>Audacity</h3>
				<p>Okay so this is a short story that makes no sense. I installed Audacity through the package manager Zypper. It didn’t work. I uninstalled and tried again. Didn’t work. I uninstalled and tried with Flatpak. Didn’t work. I uninstalled. I slept the computer and didn’t come back until a few hours later. I logged in, and Audacity was open. I did the quick audio edit I installed it for, and then closed the program. Tried to open again, and it didn’t exist because I had already uninstalled it before. Installed through Zypper again, and now it works with no issue.</p>
				<p>No idea.</p>
				<h3>Installing Mullvad VPN</h3>
				<p>Mullvad provides a Linux release in the form of a .deb for Ubuntu/Debian and a .rpm for Fedora. openSUSE also uses .rpm, but there are issues with doing that when it’s not intended for openSUSE. In this case, the distributions have packages that are named differently, so the proper way to install this is to edit the .rpm and rename the dependencies it lists. I followed a guide on how to do this exactly, but the tool I was using, rpmrebuild, would fail when trying to create the modified rpm. Again, skip a few hours of trial and error, and I found a Reddit comment mentioning issues with the specific version of rpmrebuild Zypper installs. I tried a different version, and everything worked.</p>
				<p>I don’t know how I would do anything without the random obscure Reddit comments out there.</p>
				<h3>Installing Huion Tablet Driver</h3>
				<p>It’s important to me as an artist that my pen tablet works correctly on my computer. I was avoiding setting this up, because I was afraid that this could be the thing that doesn’t work. Well, it turned out to be surprisingly easy. Huion only provides a .dep, but it turns out there’s a tool called alien that can convert this to an rpm. I did that, and the rpm installed with minimal issues. Everything works now!</p>
				<h3>LogiOps</h3>
				<p>My mouse is an MX Master 3s from Logitech, and I really love it. On Windows, I set a button to use gestures for different screenshot actions. I wanted to replicate this on my new install, and sure enough, this software called LogiOps exists. You can essentially configure all the same stuff you could with Logitech’s software on Windows, but now it feels less bloat-y. There’s no ui or anything, you just have to edit a configuration file. I think I did run into some issue to solve for this one too, but honestly I don’t remember anymore. It works now. On Windows, I was using ShareX for screenshots. On here, I’m using Spectacle. I got it to behave the same way as before, so I’m pretty happy with it</p>
				<h3>Gaming on Linux</h3>
				<p>I installed Steam and played a bit of Warframe running with Proton. Worked great! I played some I installed Prism Launcher to play Minecraft and it worked great as well. I haven’t really tried more games yet, but hopefully everything is fine. There was one small issue with these games though, and that was fullscreen. Warframe had buggy behavior after tabbing out of the game on fullscreen that I could only fix by restarting the game. Minecraft would straight up crash when I toggled fullscreen, and it would also crash when I quit the game. I have figured out what the issue was though.</p>
				<h3>Nvidia doesn’t work well with Wayland</h3>
				<p>In addition to those games, I was also having issues with OBS. Trying to open a windowed preview or fullscreen preview would crash the program. I switched my window manager from Wayland to X11, and the issues disappeared. OBS stopped crashing, Minecraft stopped crashing, and Warframe no longer had any issues. I’ve been told Wayland is generally better, but it has issues with Nvidia graphics cards. It’s a shame because I kind of do feel like X11 has some quirks too, but at least nothing is broken anymore.</p>
				<p>I guess its true that if you are building a PC with Linux in mind, you have to go AMD.</p>
				<h3>Conclusion</h3>
				<p>My experience so far on Linux has been a lot of fun. If you are a “project person,” you’ll be happy to find that doing anything on here could be a project. I really just need Affinity software to run natively on here, and then I genuinely wouldn’t use Windows again. Except for multiplayer games I guess. Idk I’m seriously considering quitting Fortnite because of the effort to boot Windows now. The experience has been pretty good so far though, especially because I already used a lot of open source software (Krita, Blender, Inkscape, OBS, LibreOffice). I definitely don’t recommend openSUSE to anyone who isn’t already a tinkerer. If you are curious about computers, like solving puzzles, and aren’t easily frustrated, openSUSE is awesome. Otherwise, Mint is probably fine I think. That’s all for today though. See ya later</p>
				<figure>
					<img src="/blogimages/052825desktop.png" alt="a desktop with a metal heart red wallpaper." style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
						<figcaption>My new PC desktop</figcaption>
					</figure>
]]>
				</description>
			</item>
			<item>
				<title>
					<![CDATA[This could be the year I switch to Linux]]>
				</title>
				<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=this-could-be-the-year-i-switch-to-linux</link>
				<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=this-could-be-the-year-i-switch-to-linux</guid>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 17:36:13 GMT</pubDate>
				<description>
					<![CDATA[<p>For a long time now, I've been considering switching to Linux for my personal computer. I grew up with Windows, and I feel very comfortable in that environment, but I think it's time to move on.</p>
					<p>I haven't switched to Windows 11 because I really like Windows 10. It's pretty much exactly the feeling I want from my computer. But, Microsoft is soon going to stop supporting Windows 10, and, I'm getting more tired with the annoying aspects of Windows. Just a few months ago, my computer refused to boot, and I had to do a sort of soft reset to fix it. It really bummed me out, and in looking up ways to fix it, I found that many people have had this experience. Sometimes, Windows just completely dies. It's weird. It's uncommon. But I don't want it to happen again.</p>
					<p>I'm a huge fan of foss, but I do rely on software that is not open source. The Affinity creative suite is hugely useful to me, but these programs do not run on Linux. This is the only reason I will not make the complete jump to Linux, and I instead plan to run a dual boot setup. I will use Windows when I have to, and Linux the rest of the time. With my new job coming up, this makes more sense to do. I will have less time and energy to work on my own creative projects, so I'll probably end up using my computer more for leisure or simpler things. </p>
					<p>It will still be a while before I do this because I want to buy another drive to make this all work nicely. In the meantime, I set up Linux on an old laptop I have. I actually did this <a href="https://flare145.com/blogpost?=on-linux" rel="nopener" target="_blank">once before</a> and made a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8g25G5yWGLc" rel="nopener" target="_blank">video about it</a>, but I'm using a different distro now. I'm now using OpenSUSE instead of Lubuntu. Surprisingly, this laptop is holding up well, so I'm glad I tried this out. I intend to someday use this on my main computer.</p>
					<p>Fun fact: I'm writing this post on my Linux laptop! I don't think I did that last time so that's fun. Overall, messing with Linux on here is best described as fun. KDE Plasma is the desktop environment I'm using, and it has so many options for customization. I love it. I can't test gaming that well on here, but I know things have gotten better through Proton. I did download VVVVVV and it played fine, but I think that wasn't through a compatibility layer? I'm not sure. </p>
					<figure>
						<img src="/blogimages/052225desktop.png" alt="A clean looking computer desktop with a firefox window containing my blog writing tool" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
							<figcaption>Screenshot of what my Linux desktop looks like</figcaption>
						</figure>
						<p>I hope that I can make my "full" switch to Linux soon. The feeling I'm getting is similar to when I was first switching to Bluesky. In like October or November, I just stopped using Twitter, and everything genuinely felt better. I somewhat feel like I helped encourage my friends to use Bluesky more by setting an example. I want to do the same now with Linux. I just have to commit. And purchase another drive. And back up my files. And get dual boot working. It might be a while.</p>
]]>
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<title>
						<![CDATA[An immense amount of focus]]>
					</title>
					<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=an-immense-amount-of-focus</link>
					<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=an-immense-amount-of-focus</guid>
					<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 17:23:43 GMT</pubDate>
					<description>
						<![CDATA[<p>The biggest thing that differentiates me today from the me of last year is my focus. I feel as though for the past year, my focus has been steadily coming back to me.</p>
						<p>This probably began with starting to read again. I attribute all of my early mental development to how much I read books as a kid. After I stopped going to school, I mostly stopped reading. Maybe that contributed a lot to brain fog I experienced afterwards. Well, maybe brain fog is the wrong term. I was definitely less focused and less motivated, but anything I worked on with passion was easy to work on. </p>
						<p>Last September, I had an interview for a job that didn’t go so well, and it motivated me a lot to get things better next time around. I think it was that energy that carried me through working on Boxkid, and then starting to read. But reading really compounded my energy and improved my mind. I was just reading Dune, a fiction novel, but it helped with activating more of my brain. Since then, my breaks have been fewer and shorter. I’ve  pretty much always been working on something, and then sometimes I loosen up to talk with friends.</p>
						<p>Currently, I’m really focused on my RSS Plaza project. It’s going well, although my pace has slowed down in the past week. I’m in the middle of working my last two weeks at my current job, so some of my free days have been spent doing a couple odd things I wanted to get done before starting the new job. Namely, getting some more clothes because my work wardrobe was not prepared for a 5 day work week.</p>
						<p>Maybe my new job is creating some kind of pressure in my mind that helps me focus on my project. Kind of like a mini version of the previously mentioned death clock, but I know that this job will obliterate my time entirely. I think this project is just interesting enough for me to stay glued to it.</p>
						<p>Working on RSS Plaza has been addicting. I’ve realized that it’s the culmination of so many things that I’ve learned over the years. I started learning HTML and CSS in 2020, and created my personal website in 2021. I didn’t see myself as a programmer, as I spent the previous years making animations in Blender. I understood how coding works, but I just hadn’t invested time into it, and didn’t see myself beginning to. So, I avoided JavaScript at first. Eventually, I learned JavaScript little by little for small features on my website. This grew until I ended up making more websites with more JavaScript. I’ve still never felt like much of a programmer until this project. After 4 years of tinkering, I’ve gained the ability to open the documentation for a JavaScript library and start building a project with relative ease. Three.js has proven to be incredibly addictive to work with, as it doesn’t take much effort at all to start rendering models and animations I create in Blender. Now, not only can I make cool stuff to look at in Blender, but I can bring them to life in on my phone in a web browser. Where Boxkid is a sort of a personal snapshot of my love for simply drawing on paper, RSS Plaza is the culmination of whats possible with the more technical skills I’ve acquired over the years.</p>
						<p>For a post about focus, I think this came out very unfocused. That’s all for now. Maybe next time I’ll talk about uhh… idk. See ya later</p>
]]>
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<title>
						<![CDATA[Death of the Deathclock]]>
					</title>
					<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=death-of-the-deathclock</link>
					<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=death-of-the-deathclock</guid>
					<pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 04:16:24 GMT</pubDate>
					<description>
						<![CDATA[<p>Many months ago, I made reference to the <a href="https://flare145.com/blogpost?=the-deathclock" rel="nopener" target="_blank">deathclock</a>. I was referring to my intention to work a labor job by April of this year, if I wasn't able to land any other job. The last few months, I've been mentally preparing for this. I still kept applying to other jobs, but I had essentially accepted that that my life was going to feel over.</p>
						<p>It's May now. I interviewed for that road work job, and didn't get a call back. This wasn't an issue with qualification or anything, they just had limited spots and I didn't apply early enough. So, for a few weeks, things felt odd. The clock made it to the end, but my life didn't end. Then, last week, things got interesting.</p>
						<p>I got a call from an employer looking to schedule an interview with me. A sign shop. It's the kind of place I've been wanting to work at. I didn't think much would come from this as I didn't have much luck in the past, but I was still going to put my best foot forward and see what comes of it. And, what came of it was probably the most successful interview I've experienced.</p>
						<p>We talked back and forth about design, art philosophy, and the role of the business. I left feeling like I had made a great impression, but they still hadn't made a decision. I was later asked to complete a short design task as a sort of test, so I saw that as a good sign. Then, just yesterday, I was offered a job! It's interesting because while I had applied for the role of designer, circumstances led them to offer me a different role. It's a bit hard to explain, but I will be assisting the shop in places that they need more assistance in. It's more about being responsible for a wide set of tasks, instead of just a design focus. Obviously I took the job, and I'm super excited to work this role in particular. It sounds very interesting, and I hope it's fulfilling. It will definitely be an upgrade from my current job, although I will have to get used to working more and having more responsibility, both of which I feel completely capable of. I might just be a little more tired for a while.</p>
						<p>So with this, the deathclock is defeated. I landed a job doing something that I want to be doing. It's incredible. I've been trying not to get too personal in my blog as of late, but this is very personal to me. It's a personal victory. And with this victory, this entire blog has now become an interesting story. It's a record of some of my ups and downs, and a record of my journey into a variety of interests. It's not entertaining, but it is interesting. To me. The guy that it's about. idk</p>
						<p>So what's next for FLARE145? A lot, lot less. I'm gonna be much more busy, and I'm going to have less energy to work on my passion projects. That said, maybe I'll get used to it, and I can pick up work on these things again later on. I fully intend to keep working on Boxkid at some point, and right now, I'm going to keep working on RSS Plaza while I can. But once I start this job, I want to prioritize doing a good job there. You might be seeing a lot less of me, but FLARE145 is unkillable. I can't stop making things. So trust me, you'll see me around.</p>
						<p>Updates on other stuff: not that much. Aside from working more hours at my current job, I've mostly been freakishly focused on RSS Plaza. It's going very smoothly right now, which makes it addicting to work on. I'll probably make another post on that soon. Or maybe I'll just keep posting about it on Bluesky because of the convenience. </p>
						<p>That's all for now. Thanks for reading and following my journey. This is the beginning of new things in my life. I'm happy. See you later</p>
]]>
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<title>
						<![CDATA[Cool three.js Project]]>
					</title>
					<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=cool-threejs-project</link>
					<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=cool-threejs-project</guid>
					<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 20:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
					<description>
						<![CDATA[<p>So lately, I’ve been working on a new code project. I know this takes time away from some of my other projects, but I just have too much energy for this to ignore it.</p>
						<p>I’ve brought this up before, but the idea is RSS Plaza. Basically, it’s an RSS feed that has a presentation inspired by Nintendo console apps like Streetpass Mii Plaza. You will be able to assign a feed to a robot character, and click on the character to see the latest post. The robots will be customization with two colors and a profile icon for their face.</p>
						<figure>
							<img src="/blogimages/042925rss1.png" alt="Three square headed robots" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
								<figcaption>Concept art for RSS Plaza</figcaption>
							</figure>
							<figure>
								<img src="/blogimages/042925rss2.png" alt="a robot with the rss icon on their screen head" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
									<figcaption>Default RSS robot character rendering in the browser</figcaption>
								</figure>
								<figure>
									<img src="/blogimages/042925rss3.png" alt="the robot sitting on grass, looking up" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
										<figcaption>a closer look at the default robot</figcaption>
									</figure>
									<p>This started happening because I suddenly started teaching myself three.js, and I immediately saw how I could make this old idea possible. I’m very happy with how it’s looking so far, I just need to be able to put in the proper functionality. I’m a little worried on that front, but my brother said he can offer coding help when it comes to actually dealing with the feed stuff, so the focus right now is getting the characters to work how I want.</p>
									<p>There’s a chance I might be getting a new job soon, and in that case, I won’t really have time to work on this. I wanted to make a post about this with these screenshots before then, but who knows. I might still be able to make this happen. I really hope so at least.</p>
]]>
								</description>
							</item>
							<item>
								<title>
									<![CDATA[Marksman drawing]]>
								</title>
								<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=marksman-drawing</link>
								<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=marksman-drawing</guid>
								<pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 03:06:02 GMT</pubDate>
								<description>
									<![CDATA[<p>I posted a drawing! Today I posted a drawing of Marksman. This is a character by <a href="https://rahimali.net" rel="nopener" target="_blank">Rahim Ali</a>.</p>
									<figure>
										<img src="https://storage.googleapis.com/flare145.com/art-images/di008.png" alt="Marksman sliding with a background of a city" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
											<figcaption>Drawing of Marksman</figcaption>
										</figure>
										<p>You can check out the <a href="https://flare145.com/artwork/di008" rel="nopener" target="_blank">artwork page</a> for more info.</p>
										<p>Now that I have the RSS feed again, I think I'll try to always make a blog post whenever I upload artwork. Just a short little post like this one to notify people that I uploaded something. It's also cool as a sort of timestamp. Anyways, that's all for now, see ya later</p>
]]>
									</description>
								</item>
								<item>
									<title>
										<![CDATA[Posting from mobile]]>
									</title>
									<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=posting-from-mobile</link>
									<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=posting-from-mobile</guid>
									<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 05:15:05 GMT</pubDate>
									<description>
										<![CDATA[<p>Okay so I used to do this occasionally. I can use the blog tool on my phone, but in order to get a post live on the website, I had to make edits to files using the GitHub website. It would take 2 commits and was just kind of annoying. Now, I have the actual website saved to my phone, and hop, I'll be able to follow the same process I do on PC, which is to update the files locally and then sync it with git. I'm doing this with Termux, which is an awesome app I've never heard of. Basically a little terminal you can download and use like Linux. </p>
										<p>Maybe this is the return of evil posts I make late at night on my phone? Probably not. I'm guessing this will still be a hassle, but we'll see. Main reason I'm trying this is because I'm having a hard time trying to sleep right now even though I feel very tired. If this works, than yay! You're reading words I wrote on my phone and uploaded with relative ease. If it doesn't work, you won't see this. </p>
										<p>Anyways uhhhh bye</p>
]]>
									</description>
								</item>
								<item>
									<title>
										<![CDATA[Activation energy]]>
									</title>
									<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=activation-energy</link>
									<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=activation-energy</guid>
									<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 02:55:44 GMT</pubDate>
									<description>
										<![CDATA[<p>Have I talked about this before? This is one of those things I could talk about forever, so maybe I will discuss this in greater detail later.</p>
										<p>I work on a wide variety of creative projects, and it’s a difficult thing to balance sometimes. There’s so much I want to make, but also so much I’d like to experience.  In science, <em>activation energy</em> is the amount of energy required to start a chemical process. I like to use this term to refer to everyday tasks, including creative projects.</p>
										<p>A task with low activation energy is something like washing dishes. Yeah it can be time consuming if there’s a lot, but its really easy to get started. Just need a sponge and some soap. A task with high activation energy might be something like fixing a car. There are so many more variables, and there’s a possibility that this task balloons into multiples steps. Most importantly, it requires more thinking.</p>
										<p>In my mind, my hierarchy of which projects to work on is pretty clear. Commissions, Boxkid, other projects, and leisure. However, I don’t distribute my time according to this order. It’s more like commissions, leisure, other projects, Boxkid. So what’s happening? I’m acting according to activation energy, prioritizing tasks that are easier to start.</p>
										<p>What sucks about this is that I’ve observed this about my life for a long time, and I came up with Boxkid to combat this. It was a project significantly less interesting than other stuff I wanted to make, but I started working on it to invest into something that was designed to have low activation energy. Of course, my most reasonable fears came true— I ballooned the scope of the idea. It’s okay, because I feel like I came up with cool stuff. The problem is that “cool stuff” requires so much more thinking. And planning. Planning sucks. </p>
										<p>Something that helps with these tougher tasks is to have more time in the day to actually get started, but that happens less on days I work. This is the main reason I haven’t worked on Boxkid much for over a week. I’m not likely to work on it much for the coming days either, but I am going to try to dedicate some time today to a little bit of planning. I want to make proper model sheets for my main characters, and now that I’ve lifted the traditional paper only restriction on myself for planning material, this should be easier to make than what I originally expected. So I’m pretty excited.</p>
										<p>I’ve been having fun writing more posts lately, but I might be slowing back down now. I want to write out some more long ones, but they are going to take a while. There are two long posts I’d like to make in particular. In one, I’d like to discuss my current stance on ai generated imagery and the future of the visual arts. I’ve been wanting to make a video on this, but my attempts at that have not gone well, so I think the post will have to do. For the second, I’ve been meaning to collect my ideas on the presence of hypersexuality on the internet. There’s a lot to discuss with this one, so it’s probably going to take me a while. I just remembered that there’s also another one I started to write about vibe-coding. That will probably show up within a week. </p>
										<p>That’s all for now, see ya later but less frequently!</p>
]]>
									</description>
								</item>
								<item>
									<title>
										<![CDATA[Microblogging vs. Miniblogging]]>
									</title>
									<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=microblogging-vs-miniblogging</link>
									<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=microblogging-vs-miniblogging</guid>
									<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 15:45:19 GMT</pubDate>
									<description>
										<![CDATA[<p>All this recent activity on my blog has made me think a bit more about what this even is.</p>
										<p>Most internet people are familiar with the term microblogging, which refers to short posts on social media platforms. Their purpose is similar to blogs, but much shorter, and much less professional, although, microblogging does have professional uses. </p>
										<p>My blog on this website is not a microblog, but I don’t see it as a regular blog either. It’s more of an in-between. Something that isn’t capped by a character limit, but is less serious than a real blog. The word I’m drawn to use is miniblog. However, it turns out that people already use that word for something else. I’ve never heard of this, but people use miniblog to mean microblog too. The words are interchangeable. I don’t like this, so from here on out, I declare this blog to be an example of a miniblog, placing it’s scale between microblogging and blogging. </p>
										<p>Did you know some people use the word nanoblog? It means the exact same thing again. Lame.</p>
										<h3>RSS stuff</h3>
										<p>Oh yeah, small update on RSS stuff. I mentioned last time that you can now subscribe to this blog as an RSS feed, but there was still a few issues I hadn’t caught. The time of posting was incorrect, so I spent some time yesterday trying to fix it. That means that posts before this one show up as being posted on the wrong day. I think it should be fine now, but I won’t know until I post this one. If this works, it actually means that you’d get a more accurate idea of when I made a post on the RSS feed than you do with this website.</p>
										<p>On the topic of RSS, I wanted to make a few recommendations. I’ve been using <a href="https://feedly.com/" rel="nopener" target="_blank">Feedly</a> to read articles on my phone during my work breaks. I can’t say much about desktop experience because I don’t use it, but I have to imagine it’s okay. My main problem with Feedly is that you miss out on features if you don’t pay for it, but I don’t notice it too much. You do need to make an account though.</p>
										<p>In searching for better ways to test my feed, I found a feed reader today that I think I might like more. You can find it at <a href="https://rss-reader.dutl.uk/" rel="nopener" target="_blank">rss-reader.dutl.uk</a>. This is a very simple RSS reader that works well on both desktop and mobile. It lacks many features from other readers, but if you just want to follow a few feeds, it’s really nice. No account is needed. If you want to save your feeds, all you need to do is bookmark the url, which updates when you add more feeds to it. IT’S ALSO OPEN SOURCE WHOOO! </p>
										<p>Sorry about that, I don’t usually get that loud. Uh thanks for reading! bruahsani </p>
]]>
									</description>
								</item>
								<item>
									<title>
										<![CDATA[RSS feed is back?]]>
									</title>
									<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=rss-feed-is-back</link>
									<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=rss-feed-is-back</guid>
									<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
									<description>
										<![CDATA[<p>For a while now, I’ve been wanting to bring back my RSS feed. You might remember that you used to be able to subscribe to my blog this way. I updated it from the post <a href="https://flare145.com/blogpost?=flare145-goes-to-chicago" rel="nopener" target="_blank">FLARE145 goes to Chicago</a> to <a href="http://flare145.com/blogpost?=cool-little-animation-for-coaxion" rel="nopener" target="_blank">Cool little animation for Coaxion</a>, but it was too big of a hassle for something that was unnecessary. Well, in trying to once again improve how I post the blog, I managed to make it much easier for me to maintain an RSS feed. So, if you use a feed reader, be sure to subscribe to my <a href="http://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="nopener" target="_blank">RSS feed</a>!</p>
										<p>I will probably actually support it for a long time now. With the improvements to my system, it’s less work to make a post, even with the added step of the RSS feed. I’ll put a proper link to it somewhere on this page too, because I don’t think I ever had one.</p>
										<p>Another reason I wanted to do this is because of my dream of making my own feed reader. I likely won’t get around to doing this ever, but I want to make a feed reader that looks like a little plaza of characters, each one representing a feed. They would be customization so you can make them look like your friends sona or something, and have them walk around with that friend’s feed. I just think it would be cool, but it’s probably impossible for me to ever make.</p>
										<p>I’ve got some stuff to do so I’ll sign off for now. Did you notice I’ve been making more posts? I’ve been in a writing mood lately. Not sure how long this will last for, but I do at least have one more post I’ve been typing out for a bit. Not sure what day I’ll post it, but probably soon. Until then, see ya</p>
]]>
									</description>
								</item>
								<item>
									<title>
										<![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2]]>
									</title>
									<link>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=nintendo-switch-2</link>
									<guid>https://flare145.com/blogpost?=nintendo-switch-2</guid>
									<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 01:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
									<description>
										<![CDATA[<p>Nintendo recently presented their new console, and I’m really excited for it.</p>
										<p>I understand that those prices are looking very high, and in particular, I see no reason for any of the accessories to be priced that high. But thankfully, I’m in a situation where a lot of the money I make is just getting saved, and I really don’t mind spending on a console and game. It would only amount to like ¾ a paycheck which I can totally do right now. The sadder thing is that if I get the new job I’m trying to get, I probably wouldn’t even have time to play it.</p>
										<p>The new Mario Kart looks so good. I was expecting a new game to be vastly different since Mario Kart 8 is the peak of the current formula, and they definitely delivered. Mario Kart is one of those games I love to play forever, and I recently got into Forza Horizon 5 in a similar way. The new game feels like a combination of both in some ways, so it’s literally peak. </p>
										<p>Donkey Kong Bonanza is also another reminder of why I’m always drawn to Nintendo games. It really is like “indie games with a budget.” What I mean is that they make really polished games that often incorporate new and unique gameplay ideas. There is not a game that you can currently play that is like Donkey Kong Bonanza. You can play other 3d platformers, but none feature the same mechanics. I’ve been thinking about destructible environments in games recently, mostly because of how they were implemented in Marvel Rivals. I think it’s one of the cooler aspects of Marvel Rivals, and I was thinking about how this feels like something that wasn’t really possible to make until now. With Nintendo, they try to look for this kind of thing. What is possible now with new hardware that wasn’t possible before. With the Switch 2 hardware, they’ve been able to make a destructible environment system that blows Marvel Rivals out of the water. Obviously, there are more constraints with Rivals because it’s designed in a way that facilitates a playable competitive map (very impressive), but I’m still really impressed with what I’ve seen in Donkey Kong. </p>
										<p>Everything is possible first on pc, and really, indie games prove that pretty much anything is possible on low spec hardware as well. But it’s the combination of quality visuals and design with unique ideas that makes me so excited about Nintendo games. I don’t like to call myself a Nintendo fan, but I am. If they stopped making good games, then I’d stop being a fan. But if you erased my memory and put games from across the industry in front of me, I’d be most drawn to Minecraft. But then after that it would probably be a Nintendo game. So yeah.</p>
										<p>Things have been getting better for 3d platformer fans though. A lot of pc games like Super Lucky’s Tale, or upcoming ones like Rolling Rascal. Even Sony’s Astrobot almost made me want to get a Playstation, but that’s the only game I’d really be interested in, so maybe in like 10 years. </p>
										<p>The closer we get to the end of support for Windows 10, the more I feel like I want to switch to Linux as my pc operating system. I now have a vision of a future where my pc is linux, and I do most of my gaming on a separate dedicated device. Currently, something like a Steam Deck would be best for this, but seeing the performance of the Switch 2, I can see a near future where I do this with the Switch. Just an interesting idea.</p>
										<p>That’s all for now. Just wanted to ramble because I’m really excited. The cool thing about being older is that you can actually wait for things you “can’t wait for.” In the mean time, I’ve got peak to play (Crab Champions).</p>]]>
									</description>
								</item>
							</channel>
						</rss>