<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
	<link type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" id="dark-mode-custom-link"/>
	<link type="text/css" rel="stylesheet" id="dark-mode-general-link"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-custom-style"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-native-style"/>
	<style lang="en" type="text/css" id="dark-mode-native-sheet"/>
	<channel>
		<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
		<atom:link href="http://flare145.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
		<link>http://flare145.com</link>
		<description>Official rss feed for FLARE145'S blog! Updates on new projects or random boring things.</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<image>
			<url>http://flare145.com/res/blogicon128.png</url>
			<title>FLARE145 - Blog</title>
			<link>https://flare145.com/</link>
			<width>128</width>
			<height>128</height>
		</image>
		<item>
			<title>FLARE145 goes to Chicago</title>
			<link>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=flare145-goes-to-chicago</link>
			<guid>http://flare145.com/blogpost?=flare145-goes-to-chicago</guid>
			<description>
				<![CDATA[ <p class="date">7/4/23</p>
<p>I been in Chicago for the past week and I'm staying for like two more. I'm here because I'm visiting family and I've been having a great time.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/070423chicago.png" alt="A view of the city of chicago" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>The windy city</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I have plenty of free time considering I'm on vacation and all, so of course I started to work on random projects. First, I've been working on a tattoo design for some friends. I don't really have a deadline for that so it tends to be something I work on only when I feel like it. Next, I've been messing with making a logo for <a href="https://www.moddb.com/company/conc-studios" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Coaxion</a>, which is currently still known as Concussion Studios. They are currently rebranding, so from this point forward I will only refer to them as Coaxion. Multiple people are working on the logo, so my designs might not ever make it. So here's a look at one of them for funsies.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/070423coaxion.png" alt="Coaxion" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>A wip version of the logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Speaking of Coaxion, they just showed <a href="https://www.moddb.com/mods/deathmatch-classic-refragged" rel="noopener" target="_blank">DMCR</a> at <a href="https://www.dokomi.de/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Dokomi</a>, which is a big anime expo in Germany. They had these cool demo machines for the game which where decorated with some the achievement icons I designed a while back. It's trippy to see something I worked on out in the world. I'm happy for the Coaxion people and <a href="https://pjx.carrd.co/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">PJX</a>, who is the dev who represented at Dokomi.</p>
<figure>
  <img src="/blogimages/070423dokomi.png" alt="Demo machines for DMCR" style="width:60vmin; display:inline; max-width:790px;">
  <figcaption>Taken by PJX at Dokomi 2023</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Okay last thing. If you follow me on twitter you know that I'm really into the idea of Boxkid. I talked about this last blogpost, but it's basically just a webcomic idea. While I don't feel comfortable actually starting the comic from where I am, I can still work on all of the surrounding aspects. Which is a lot actually. Mainly the website. I haven't bought a domain for it yet but it's currently live on <a href="http://boxkid.flare145.com" rel="noopener" target="_blank">boxkid.flare145.com</a>. It's very much a work in progress, although the plan for the finished website probably won't look very impressive. I just need to be able to serve pages for people to read. But yeah check it out if you want to see my concept images.</p>
<p>And that's about it. Stay tuned for more info on Boxkid as that is the main thing I'm currently passionate about. Until next time</p> ]]>
			</description>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>